what's up everybody this video is all
about the like I'm coach brick address
aka the glue guy and in this video I
want to cover how we use the leg press
here at glute lab now first and foremost
I don't consider the lake press an
accessory lift I don't like that
terminology we have everyone like press
here and I considered a primary lift it
fills the quads it builds the glutes it
works them uniquely you can do a double
leg you can do a single leg and we have
girls using six plates per side a lot of
girls using five plates per side and
plenty also using four plates per side
they get very strong when you lake press
week in and week out with progressive
overload now we have this Cybex that
they actually call this the squat press
but it's it's a leg press and we use it
because it's got you know a couple
different pivot points and therefore it
moves with your body in short it's the
most comfortable way to lake press in my
opinion it's superior than the typical
45-degree slats
and as one of my powerlifting friend
Steve clevis said this was built for the
human body so this is your basic leg
press setup notice jamie's feet are
straight and it's kind of bisects the
platform vertically and horizontally so
her feet are nice and squared up with
her hips and in the middle and this is
your basic leg press she's gonna go down
and do a few reps and she's gonna go
nice and deep now if you can see her low
back does not round and this is the main
thing you want to go as deep as possible
without losing your lumbar curvature or
posterior pelvic tilt inc so Jamie has
great hip flexion mobility so she can go
nice and deep if you can't if you feel
yourself coming off your your butt
tucking under and coming off the path
you're going too deep so just go as deep
as your body allows and don't lock out
the knees leave them up slight then
knows the two main things to keep you
safe during the leg press
so what if you want to make the lake
press more quad dominant a lot of guys
do leg press four quads they want big
quads how can you work the quads more
with a leg press well you do so by
taking a narrow stance and putting your
feet low on the platform so as you can
see Jamie is now not positioned in the
middle she's down low she's gonna
perform a few reps making sure to go
deep now as you can see here this way
requires a lot of dorsiflexion mobility
but it's gonna work the quads very well
[Music]
bonus tip three bras we want to really
annihilate your quads is to use Olympic
shoes
[Music]
if you use Olympic shoes they have high
heels this is gonna make it more quad
Emily you combine that with a low floor
placement and your quads will be
screaming I remember the first time I
did
leg press little with the Olympic shoes
I had to use much less weight but my
quads were burning for like 30 minutes
afterward what if you want to make it
less blood dominated more hamstring
dominant in this case you're gonna go
high and wide Jamie's going to perform a
few reps making sure to keep the knees
out and this takes the quads out of it a
little bit and you'll feel a stretch in
your hamstrings
thus working them a bit and now finally
what if you want to make it more glute
dominant you want to feel like pressing
your glutes not your quads or hammies
we're gonna put on a glute look this is
the large extra large you want the level
1 2 or 3 Jamie here is using the level 1
she's got her feet out wide and as you
can see as she descends she's gonna
flare her knees out far
now this is going to help you feel the
leg press working your glutes more I
call this torque doubling because the
glutes are working to perform hip
extension but they're also pushing out
against the bands to carry out hip
abduction so you're putting double duty
on the glutes making them work hard to
hip extend and hip abduct at the same
time now let's talk about single leg leg
rest variations so the most basic
variation is just centering your foot
and having it straight the other leg is
off to the side okay perform a few reps
now some people feel it more when they
turn the foot in a little bit okay do
you like it a little bit more this way
puts a little bit bigger stretch on the
glute but not everyone likes it more
that way some people prefer the single
leg leg press more when they put their
foot out and turn down they put their
foot out line and turn out like this
perform a few reps
and some people feel their glutes
working a lot more in particular while
they perform this variation and finally
we have the sideways variation which I
used to not like that much but so many
of my female clients liked it that I
actually changed my mind
so this is done like this we're actually
turn to the side an interesting thing
about this is it's you kind of abduct a
little bit as you come up
so this is an option the foot is turned
in your turn to the side obviously you
start with your stronger leg and match
with the weaker leg and last but not
least we have the B stance variations
which they make it easier at the bottom
but then you kind of take over towards
the top with the one leg so on the side
backseat you do B stance like this okay
she's gonna perform a few reps and what
you'll find is that at the bottom you
give yourself a little bit of assistance
but it's still mostly single leg you can
also put this foot with the side X you
can put here come up on your toes
you can put it here and just give
yourself just a little bit of assistance
[Music]
what you're looking for with these
dances to put around 78 to 80 percent of
the force on the one leg and about 20
percent assistance with the other leg
[Music]
now let's talk sets and reps so at blue
lab we perform pyramids straight sets
and drop sets with the leg press and
sometimes we do enhance descent rates
with the pyramids an example is 10 8 6
15 so you'll start out with the weight
you can get for 10 reps you'll add some
more weight do 8 reps after a couple
minutes rest rest a couple more minutes
go heavier do 6 reps and then strip some
weight off and then do 15 reps so that's
a pyramid for straight sets maybe we do
4 sets of 10 and you can do that with a
sending weight or the same way each set
using the same way is a little bit
tougher and with drop sets you'll load a
bunch of plates on the bar you'll
perform as many reps as you can see
there's 5 5 plates on each side say you
perform 10 reps you strip a plate down
now you get 10 more reps you strip a
plate down 10 more reps and then finally
you strip another plate and get 10 more
so you do 10 10 10 10 that would be 40
reps with the leg press
decreasing loads so you're getting heavy
moderate lighter loads that method is
brutal we don't do as many sets if we do
drop sets maybe two sets of a drop set
like that and that's it and with the
enhanced eccentric there's two ways to
do it you can either do the two up 1
down method where you where you perform
the concentric rope with two legs and
then lower with one leg or you can put
both legs on there that I will be
pushing down on the way down see when we
lower it slowly with me pushing down and
then I let go for the way up that was
all about the leg press I hope you enjoy
the video
[Music]